KESHMA RATHOD

1517 Split Oak Ln, Apt. G, Henrico VA 23229

Mob: +1 804 496 9074 • Email: <u>keshmadrathod@gmail.com</u>

An enthusiastic professional offering over **5 years 5 month** of IT experience; aspiring to establish a career in a growth oriented organization to utilize acquired skills and knowledge in achieving organizational goals, while attaining personal and professional growth which provides an opportunity for enhancing learning graph and career advancement.

- Completed Masters in Computer Science in Dec 2019 from Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU), VA.
- Acquired Data Science certification as part of Master's degree program.
- Worked as a **Senior Software Engineer** in Accenture Ltd.
- 4.9+ years of experience in **SQL server**, **SSIS**, **SSRS**, **MS Access and Visual Basic** platform working in all the various phases of SDLC.
- Strong analytical skills coupled with an impressive commitment to excellence.
- Ability to learn, work and advance in fast paced busy environment.
- Strong technical and analytical skills, a quick learning ability coupled with continuous hard work and has the right focus and determination to achieve the set targets.
- Experience in client interaction.
- Proven ability to work under pressure to meet the deadlines.

SKILLS

Technology SQL SERVER 2008, SSIS, SSRS, MS access and RDBMS **Language** Python, R, Visual Basic 6.0, VBA, ASP.Net, C#, C, C++,

Database SQL Server 2005, SQL SERVER 2008

Tools SQL SERVER 2008 Business Intelligence, Ez-Trac, BMC Remedy

OS/Environment Microsoft Windows

INNOVATIONS

1. Six Sigma Green Belt Value Innovation

Successfully completed the Green Belt value innovation of Microsoft Access project for CA Capital Fleet Services, Eden Prairie, Minnesota client.

2. Six Sigma Lean Value Innovation

Successfully completed the Lean innovation for CA internal process by creating a MACRO and automating it.

CERTIFICATIONS

- ➤ Data Science Certification at VCU as part of Master's degree program.
- ➤ Level-1 certified in iGATE Insurance training.
- ➤ Level-1 certified in iGATE RDBMS training.
- > IGATE internal training in PL/SQL and SQL tuning.

AWARDS

- Awarded recognition twice for focuses on delivering excellence for Praxair project.
- Awarded Dream Team Award for Motorola EMB Services.
- Awarded Pat on the Back Award for Microsoft Access project.
- Awarded certificate for Green Belt Value Innovation Project.
- Awarded certificate for Lean Value Innovation Project.

EDUCATION

- Completed Masters in Computer Science at Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU), VA.
- ➤ Bachelors of Science in Information Technology (BSc.I.T), Mumbai University, India in 2010.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Employer: Accenture Services Ltd, India
Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Duration: Oct 2014 – Dec 2015

Job Profile:

✓ Development

Requirement AnalysisDesigning and Coding

✓ Testing (Preparing High Level test cases for Client)

✓ Documentation

✓ Maintenance and Application Support

Key Deliverables:

- ✓ Responsible for On-time deliveries.
- ✓ Responsible for first time right (FTR) delivery while meeting all client requirements.
- ✓ Improve productivity.
- ✓ Responsible for Enhancement & Configuration of Existing Scenarios.
- ✓ Functional Testing of Development Tasks.
- ✓ Responsible for Output determination.
- ✓ Replicating the error in pre-production instances.
- ✓ Resolving production issue under SLA timelines.

CORPORATE PROJECTS

Project 1: Praxair Cylinder Tracking-PCT

Client : Praxair
Platform : Windows

Team Size : 2(Offshore), 1(Onsite Coordinator)

Type : Development

Duration : Oct 2014 – Dec 2015

Tools and Technology: SQL Server BI Development Studio (BIDS), MS Visual Studio 2010/2008, SSIS, SSRS, SQL

Server 2000/2005/2008.

Version Control : **T**eam Foundation Server (TFS).

Employer : Accenture Services Ltd

Project Description: Praxair GCT II Data Migration

Praxair has many instances of asset tracking software. The new system is a multi-tenant system and data from ALL instances MUST be merged into a single database. The data migration will handle all issues related to merging the ALL instances into a single instance. It is important to note that each instance is comprised of a Master database and a Client database and is a multi-tenant environment at the country/region level.

Responsibilities:

- > Designed, Implemented and tested SSIS packages for loading data from the individual database into the MDS
- > Designed, Implemented and tested SSIS packages for loading data to the intermediate database.
- Designed, Implemented and tested SSIS packages for loading data to the global database.
- ➤ Designed, Implemented and tested Interfaces using SSIS.
- ➤ Conducted a self-review of the packages.

- > Created SSIS packages to automate the Import and Export of data to and from SQL Server 2008 using SSIS tools like Import and Export Wizard, Package Installation and BIDS.
- > Created jobs, SQL Mail, Alerts and schedule SSIS Packages using SQL Server Agent.
- > Execute migration for the region working on and provide the backups of the migrated database to the Client and the team.

Project 2: TPA Inspro

Client : Individual Insurance Companies

Platform: Windows

Team Size : 12(Offshore), 4(Onsite Coordinator)

Type : Development

Duration : Nov 2012 – Sep 2014

Tools and Technology: SQL Server BI Development Studio (BIDS), MS Visual Studio2010/2008, SSIS, SSRS, SQL

Server 2000/2005/2008.

Version Control : Subversion (SVN).

Employer : IGATE Global Solutions Ltd

Project Description: TPA Inspro

Corporate Health Care services a fully owned subsidiary of IGATE Computer System, which provides Third Party Insurance Administration Services for Universal American and other insurance corporations. The Objective of the project is to replace CAPSIL - a Main Frame Based Insurance Administrative application with a more advanced InsPro Application

Responsibilities:

- > Designed, Implemented and maintained Tables, Stored procedures, Functions, Indexes, Views, etc.
- > Designed, Implemented and tested SSIS packages for loading data to the intermediate database.
- ➤ Designed, Implemented and tested SSIS packages for loading data to the Reporting Database used to generate Reports and Interfaces.
- Designed, Implemented and tested Interfaces using SSIS.
- ➤ Designed, Implemented and tested Reports using SSRS.
- ➤ FTPed the report created to the given location.
- Creating Technical designed document for the interfaces and the reports and maintaining them.
- Creating Unit test cases document for the interfaces and the reports and maintaining them.
- ➤ Conducted a self-review of the interfaces and the reports created and updated the UTC.
- > Created SSIS packages to automate the Import and Export of data to and from SQL Server 2008 using SSIS tools like Import and Export Wizard, Package Installation and BIDS.
- Created jobs, SQL Mail, Alerts and schedule SSIS Packages using SQL Server Agent.

Project 3: Microsoft Access (GE General Electric - GE)

Client: GE Capital Fleet Services, Eden Prairie, Minnesota

Platform: Windows

Team Size: 1(Offshore), 1(Onsite Coordinator)

Type: Production Support/Maintenance and Enhancement

Duration: Mar. 2011 – Oct. 2012

Tools and Technology: Microsoft Access, SQL Server, VBA (Visual Basic for Application), Oracle, Ez-trac Tool

Employer: IGATE Global Solutions Ltd.

Project Description: Microsoft Access

This project mainly involves maintaining/updating information regarding different processes like licensing, titling, stock purchase and sell out, vehicle management. It also includes enhancing the requirements given by the users. There are almost 160+ applications in 'MS Access Fleet GE' project. The primary objective of the project is to maintain all these applications by solving the tickets raised by the users and also developing parts of the applications as mentioned in the client's enhancement.

Responsibilities:

➤ Communicating with Onsite Coordinator.

- ➤ Analysis of the Business Requirements.
- ➤ Solving the Support Request raised by the clients.
- > Constructing Programs for Change Request based on the technical specifications to add new functionalities or modifying the existing business logic raised by the user.
- Testing for the Code changes.
- ➤ Conduct a self-review of the changes made.
- ➤ Maintaining the defect log for the project.
- ➤ Updating the Ez-trac application according to the Service Request/Change Request status.
- ➤ Monitoring the production running jobs.
- > Maintain the updated version of all the documents, which are implemented in the project.
- ➤ Update all the project related documents in Ez-trac, the request-tracking tool.
- ➤ Update all the request documents in CA libraries for future reference purpose.
- ➤ Periodic back up of all the applications of MS Access in a Start team tool.
- ➤ Maintaining the Value Innovation documents and ideas.

Project 4: Canada Risk (GE)

Client : GE Capital Fleet Services, Eden Prairie, Minnesota

Platform : Windows NT 4.0 Server

Team Size : 2(Offshore), 1(Onsite Coordinator)

Type : Development

Duration : Feb 2011-Mar 2011

Tools and Technology : PL/SQL and Appworx

Employer : IGATE Global Solutions Ltd

Project Description:

GE Capital Fleet Services (GE CFS) is a US based organization headquartered at Eden Prairie, Minnesota (USA) and has its business spread over US, Canada, Mexico, Europe, Japan, Australia and New Zealand. Leasing vehicles to corporate clients encompasses the primary business of this organization. In addition, GE CFS provides many add-on services to their customer viz. credit cards for fuel, assistance in case of vehicle breakdown, direct payments to concerned agencies in case of traffic violations etc. With more than 1.3 million vehicles under lease and service management through world-wide operations, GE CFS is one of the world's top leasing organizations. To cater to its business needs, GE CFS maintains a central database covering the different aspects of its business that has an interface with the clients through many applications. These applications are developed on various hardware platforms viz. IBM Mainframe, SUN and software technologies viz. traditional mainframe environment of Batch processing, Client/Server Architecture, Web technology, BI etc.

Responsibilities:

- ➤ Communicating with Onsite Coordinator.
- ➤ Analysis of the Business Requirements
- ➤ Developing the queries in PL/SQL.
- Creating test cases.
- ➤ Testing the queries based on the test cases.
- ➤ Conduct unit testing and peer to peer testing on the queries.
- ➤ Update all the request documents in CA libraries for future reference purpose.

Project 5: DFW (Motorola Dispatch for Windows Service)

Client : Motorola, USA
Platform : Windows NT Server

Team Size : 5(Offshore), 1(Onsite Coordinator), 10(Onsite Client) **Type** : Production Support/Maintenance and Enhancement

Duration : September 2010 to January 2011

Tools and Technology: Visual Studio 6.0, SQL Server, Java, Oracle, Active Server Pages, BMC

Employer : IGATE Global Solutions Ltd.

Project Description:

Dispatch for Windows (DFW) is a group of custom applications, which serves as the User Interface for accessing Motorola's service applications. The applications designed and developed by Motorola Service's I.S. Group, are written using the latest technologies and software.

Due to the large size of the application functionality and the diverse functions along with the system performance it can deliver, the entire system was modularized into diverse programs:

- > 'DFW Admin' It is basically the setup needed to run the operations viz. employee creation, code creation, etc.
- ➤ 'DFW Core' It is the main application. It is designed for speed input.
- ➤ Web Pages These are designed for Express setup as well as functionality that are not done every day. In many cases more setup functionality is included.
- ➤ QBE (Report Writer) This is the report writer tool with DFW. Using this tool the user can create and schedule reports to be sent automatically.
- ➤ Parts Entry Is a parts entry screen used by the engineer on the line.

Each program is able to call sub-programs, as needed. This design reduced the overhead required on a specific user's PC and improves system performance. DFW also interacts with systems such as My Symbol Care, Clarify, LINUX, Actuate Reports & many others.

Responsibilities:

- > Requirements and Analysis Understanding the requirements of the client/project.
- > Interacting with the client & onsite team members on various forums to discuss the status of the project, clarify any queries regarding the functionality, communicating status of project etc.
- Solving the Tickets raised by the client.
- ➤ Maintain the defect log for the Project/Tracker.
- ➤ Updating BMC according to the Ticket/Tracker Status.
- Creating SPD (Short Project Document) and uploading them on Compass location.
- Monitoring Servers.
- ➤ Developing New Enhancement according to Client requirement.
- > Interacted with business leads and users to understand existing business processes.
- > Send deployment checklist after all the enhancements are complete to ensure proper migration between environments.
- Unit testing & Integration Testing.
- Production move for critical projects with zero issues.
- Maintain the updated version of all the documents, which are implemented in the project.
- ➤ Update all the tickets related documents in BMC, the ticket-tracking tool.
- Periodic back up of all the applications.

CONTACT DETAILS

Mobile No: +1 804 496 9074

Email: <u>keshmadrathod@gmail.com</u>